<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enrico Ruggieri</title><link>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/</link><description>Recent content on Enrico Ruggieri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.enricoruggieri.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mantova II: Claudio Monteverdi</title><link>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/post/2023-mantova-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/post/2023-mantova-ii/</guid><description>Claudio Monteverdi is considered one of the pioneers of the Baroque style and the development of the melodramma, the origin of the opera. However also his contribution to the Renaissance madrigal style was substantial both in number and in quality.
Through the performing of his books of Madrigals one can hear the echoes of great masters such as Cipriano de Rore and Luca Marenzio and the influence of his contemporary Giaches de Wert.</description></item><item><title>Mantova I: Giaches de Wert</title><link>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/post/2022-mantova-i/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/post/2022-mantova-i/</guid><description>Madrigale Den Haag will perform madrigals by the most prominent musician in Mantua of the mid 16th century: Giaches de Wert.
He was known for his highly expressive musical language, great contrasts and declamatory style. He seemed to have reached the perfect match between poetry and music in the madrigal style. The music of his teacher, Cipriano de Rore, and together with the music of the musicians who further developed his style, like Claudio Monterverdi, will bring the listener closer to that fascinating style, to the music of the Duchy of Mantua and the famous Sforza family court.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/about/</guid><description>Enrico Ruggieri Music has always been a big part of my life since I was 6 years old.
I grew up playing piano, classical and jazz. During the day I studied Bach and Mozart and in the night I played my own music in clubs. I joined my first choir when I was 12. At 17 I conducted for the first time. That experience was life changing and led me to professional conducting.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.enricoruggieri.com/contact/</guid><description>Send me a message, I will get back to you as soon as I can. Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message</description></item></channel></rss>